Zheng (Thomas) Tang

RESEARCH SCIENTIST - AMAZON ONE · EXPERT IN COMPUTER VISION AND MACHINE LEARNING

Amazon - Coral (SEA68), 2201 6th Ave, Seattle, WA 98121, USA

🛛 (+1) 206-669-5590 | 🔀 tangzhengthomas@gmail.com | 🏶 zhengthomastang.github.io | 🖸 zhengthomastang | 🛅 zhengthomastang

Summary_

Current Research Scientist - Amazon One at Amazon · Ph.D. in Electrical & Computer Engineering at the University of Washington (Advisor: Prof. Jenq-Neng Hwang) · 9-month internship at NVIDIA with papers accepted to CVPR'19 and ICCV'19 · 15 publications and 2 U.S. patents (pending) · Associate Editor of TCSVT · Member of the Organizing Committee for the Al City Challenge Workshops in CVPR · Leader of the winning team at the 2nd Al City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18 · Finalist of 2 Best Student Paper Awards at ICPR'16

Education

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2019

- Advised by Prof. Jeng-Neng Hwang (IEEE Fellow) at the Information Processing Lab
- Dissertation topic: Robust Video Object Tracking via Camera Self-Calibration

University of Washington (UW)

Seattle, WA, USA

M.S. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Mar. 2016

• GPA: 3.83/4.0

Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT)

Beijing, China

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

• GPA: 88.73/100

Queen Mary University of London (QMUL)

London, UK

B.S. IN TELECOMMUNICATIONS ENGINEERING WITH MANAGEMENT (JOINT PROGRAMME)

Sep. 2010 - Jun. 2014

· First Class Honours

Work Experience_

Amazon Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH SCIENTIST - AMAZON ONE

Jul. 2019 - PRESENT

- Working on the research team for Amazon One, a fast and convenient identity service using people's palm for payment, entry and more
- · Invented a novel way to utilize various modalities of sensor data for automated user identification that was filed for a U.S. patent

NVIDIA Santa Clara, CA, USA

INTELLIGENT VIDEO ANALYTICS INTERN

Jun. 2018 - Mar. 2019

INTELLIGENT VIDEO ANALTTICS INTERN

- Created CityFlow, a city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera (MTMC) vehicle tracking and ReID, accepted to CVPR'19 (Oral)
- Proposed PAMTRI, a pose-aware multi-task network for vehicle ReID using highly randomized synthetic data, accepted to ICCV'19
- Joined the Organizing Committee of the 4th AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'20 that attracted 315 participating teams across 37 countries

University of Washington

Seattle, WA, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jun. 2015 - Jun. 2018

- Developed evolutionary camera calibration and clustering-based data association for vehicle tracking using fusion of visual and semantic features that achieved rank #1 in Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis) of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Designed multi-camera tracking based on fusion of adaptive appearance models, CNN features and license plate information that achieved rank #1 in Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID) of the 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18
- Built a 3D human pose estimator to enable overlaying AR for medical simulation under 6-DoF camera motion, where a two-step evolutionary pose optimization for camera and humans (2EPOCH) is proposed (funded by ArchieMD Inc.)
- Proposed evolutionary camera self-calibration from tracking of humans to automatically back project 2D trajectories into 3D, which was a
 finalist of 2 Best Student Paper Awards at ICPR'16 (funded by Prism Skylabs)
- Invented an adaptive segmentation and tracking algorithm based on multi-kernel feedback that achieved top single-camera tracking accuracy (74.82%) on the NLPR_MCT benchmark (funded by Madrona Venture Group)

Professional Service _

IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology (TCSVT)

Remote

ASSOCIATE EDITOR

Jan. 2021 - PRESENT

- Promptly assigned papers for review and offered publication decisions that helped reduce decision-making time by 52.5 days than in 2019
- Provided active feedback to the editors on the innovation, coverage and quality of papers to help support the impact factor of 4.133

Selected Publications

JOURNAL ARTICLES

MOANA: An online learned adaptive appearance model for robust multiple object tracking in 3D

Zheng Tang, Jeng-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 31934-31945. 2019

ESTHER: Joint camera self-calibration and automatic radial distortion correction from tracking of walking humans

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang

IEEE Access 7.1 (2019) pp. 10754-10766. 2019

Online-learning-based human tracking across non-overlapping cameras

Young-Gun Lee, Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang

TCSVT 28.10 (2018) pp. 2870-2883. 2018

CONFERENCE PAPERS

The 4th AI City Challenge

Milind Naphade, Shuo Wang, David C. Anastasiu, Zheng Tang, Ming-Ching Chang, Xiaodong Yang, Liang Zheng, Anuj Sharma, Rama Chellappa, Pranamesh Chakraborty

Proc. CVPR Workshops, 2020, Virtual

PAMTRI: Pose-aware multi-task learning for vehicle re-identification using highly randomized synthetic data

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Stan Birchfield, Jonathan Tremblay, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang *Proc. ICCV*, pp. 211–220, 2019, Seoul, Korea

CityFlow: A city-scale benchmark for multi-target multi-camera vehicle tracking and re-identification

Zheng Tang, Milind Naphade, Ming-Yu Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Stan Birchfield, Shuo Wang, Ratnesh Kumar, David Anastasiu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR, pp. 8797-8806, 2019, Long Beach, CA, USA

Joint multi-view people tracking and pose estimation for 3D scene reconstruction

Zheng Tang, Renshu Gu, Jenq-Neng Hwang

Proc. ICME, pp. 1-6, 2018, San Diego, CA, USA

Single-camera and inter-camera vehicle tracking and 3D speed estimation based on fusion of visual and semantic features

Zheng Tang, Gaoang Wang, Hao Xiao, Aotian Zheng, Jeng-Neng Hwang

Proc. CVPR Workshops, pp. 108-115, 2018, Salt Lake City, UT, USA

Multiple-kernel adaptive segmentation and tracking (MAST) for robust object tracking

Zheng Tang, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Jen-Hui Chuang

Proc. ICASSP, pp. 1115-1119, 2016, Shanghai, China

Camera self-calibration from tracking of moving persons

Zheng Tang, Yen-Shuo Lin, Kuan-Hui Lee, Jenq-Neng Hwang, Jen-Hui Chuang, Zhijun Fang

Proc. ICPR, pp. 260-265, 2016, Cancún, México

Patents

Utilizing Sensor Data for Automated User Identification

Zheng Tang, Prithviraj Banerjee, Manoj Aggarwal, Gerard Medioni

U.S. Patent Application No. 17/209,845 (Pending), 2021

Neural Network System for Object Identification

Zheng Tang, Stan Birchfield, William Hodge, Ratnesh Kumar, Milind Naphade, Jonathan Tremblay, Shuo Wang, Xiaodong Yang U.S. Patent Application No. 16/442,375 (Pending), 2019

Honors & Awards _

2019	People's Choice Award , Code for the Kingdom (C4TK) Hackathon	Seattle, WA, USA
2018	Winner of Track 1 (Traffic Flow Analysis), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake City, UT, USA
2018	Winner of Track 3 (Multi-camera Vehicle Detection & ReID), 2nd AI City Challenge Workshop in CVPR'18	Salt Lake City, UT, USA
2017	Winner of Track 2 (AI City Applications), 1st AI City Challenge Workshop in SmartWorld'17	San Francisco, CA, USA
2016	Finalist IBM Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16	Cancún, México
2016	Finalist Intel Best Track 3 Student Paper Award, ICPR'16	Cancún, México

Skills

Programming	Python (expert), C/C++ (expert), Java (proficient), JavaScript (proficient), MATLAB (expert), LTEX(expert)
Frameworks & Tools	PyTorch (expert), TensorFlow (expert), MXNet (proficient), Caffe (proficient), Git (expert), React (proficient)
Languages	English (proficient), Mandarin (native), Cantonese (native), Spanish (elementary)